Register of the Daniel Lerner collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Captured German Documents, 1944-1945 (Boxes 1-9)
  - PID-File (Folder 5: 2)
    - Numbered
      - German staff plans for "German military government in Great Britain" (#75) (), 1945 September 2
      - Ribbentrop on "certainty" of German victory over Russia (#76) (), 1945 September 1 (Folder 5: 6)
      - Göring, Rintelen, and Gen. Pariani re political and military plans for Europe (#77) (), 1945 September 13
      - Telegrams between Foreign Minister Schwerin-Krosigk and Ambassador in Tokyo Stahmer, (#78) (1945 September 9), 4-10 May 1945
      - German interest in Luxembourg after reoccupation of Rhineland by German Army (#79) (), 1945 September 11
      - Reasons for Gauleiter Bohle's dismissal from Foreign Office (#80) (), 1945 September 10
      - Round-up of former Social Democrats, Communists, and trade union officials, (#81) (1945 September 11), August 1944
      - Duplicates (#82)
      - Duplicates (#83)
      - Foreign workers in Northern Germany (#84) (), 1945 September 13
      - Strife between party members (#85) (), 1945 September 15
      - Julius Streichar's attacks on Göring and Lammers (#86) (), 1945 September 15
      - German interference in Austrian affairs, (#87) (1945 September 21), 1937
      - Letters to Schwerin-Krosigk from Kaltenbrunner, Thierack, and Major Hueldner, re Putsch (#88) (1945 September 15), July 1944
      - Legality of Hitler's offices of Chancellor and Supreme Head of State, and of Doenitz as his successor (#89) (), 1945 September 15
      - List of comments available on Schwerin-Krosigk (#90) (), 1945 September 21
      - German interference in Austrian affairs, (#91) (1945 September 21), 1935-1938
      - Himmler on Degrelle. Letter to Lemmers, (#92) (1945 September 19), 25 March 1943
      - Position of Bormann, after departure of Hess (#93) (), 1945 September 27
      - Duplicates (#94)
      - Duplicates (#95)
      - German use of a pastoral letter for anti-clerical abuse (#96) (), 1945 September 25
      - Aide-memoire on a speech of Dr. Frank, Gov. Gen. of Poland, (#97), May 1941
      - National Socialist views on the Confessional Church, (#98) (1945 October 5), 23 August 1936
      - Dittmar on propaganda, Hamburg, (#99) (1945 October 5), 21 October 1944
      - No moral scruples permissible in war (Admiral v. Reuter) (#100) (), 1945 October 5 (Folder 5: 7)
      - Greiser to leaders on methods for administration of Poland (#101) (), 1945 October 5
      - Duplicates (#102)
      - Growing distrust between Hitler and Army,; proposals to remove this by turning Panzer Grenadier Div. "Grossdeutschland" into elite Corps of Army (as against the Waffen-SS) (#103) (1945 October 5), June 1943
      - Jodl's directive,, for OKW communiqués (#104) (1945 October 4), 25 October 1944
      - Jodl's personal notes on activities of individuals heading for a military putsch (#105) (), 1945 October 9
      - , Boehme informs Jodl and Keitel of his refusal to obey orders re Sweden and Norway (#106) (1945 October 5), 7 May 1945
      - A discourse on war (anonymous) (#107) (), 1945 October 5
      - Criticism by high-ranking Russian officers of Germany's propaganda in Eastern territories and recommendations for setting up Russian puppet government, (#108) (1945 October 15), November 1942
      - German civilian morale after Stalingrad, late (#109) (1945 October 19), 1942-1943
      - General Weiss condemns policy & treatment of population in occupied areas of Russia, particularly Ukraine (#110) (), 1945 October 10
      - Three decrees to Commandants of concentration camps, (#111) (1945 October 11), 1942
      - Reimann report to Hitler on black market in Paris, (#112), February-April 1943
      - Klage's farewell letter to Hitler (#113) (), 1945 October 6
      - Description of the retreat from Moscow (5th Corps) (#114) (), 1945 October 6
      - Duplicates (#115)
      - Transport of Belgian gold from Marseilles to Berlin, (#116), October 1941
      - Abetz suggests "Femgericht" in France to avenge murders of Germans (#117) (), 1945 October 20
      - Hitler orders destruction of historic Shrine at Kiev, (#118) (1945 October 13), October 1941
      - Battle for preservation by Gen. Winter re policy in areas of German and looted works of art, valuables, and documents in Austrian saltmines, German policy of seizure of art treasures (#119) (), 1945 October 18
      - Memorandum by Gen. Winter re policy in areas of France and Belgium expected to be re-occupied during Rundstedt's Ardennes offensive (#120) (), 1945 October 25
      - Von Schirach's views on art at exhibition in Düsseldorf, (#121) (1945 October 25), 1941
      - Killing of inmates in mental asylums (#122)
      - German difficulties in Denmark (#123) (), 1945 October 25
      - German plans () for French participation in war against Britain (#124) (1945 October 15), 1940
      - Plan for the final solution of the Jewish Problem, (#125) (1945 October 16), 1942
      - German Secret Rearmament (#126) (1945 October 25), 1924-1933
      - German policy in Poland (#127) (1945 October 27), 1930-1945
      - Expulsion order for Jews in Poland (#128) (), 1945 October 26
      - Evacuation of civilian population west of the Rhine during the Allied advance in Germany. Letters and orders by Hitler, Bormann, Keital, and Ley, (#129) (1945 October 30), February-March 1945
      - Göring wishes to set up special commandos to operate among the hostile population behind the line in Russia and to commit murder, arson, and rape, (#130) (1945 November 3), September 1948
      - Means of dealing with POWs guilty of insubordination and provocative behavior (#131) (), 1945 November 3
      - "Aryanisation" of Jewish property in Gau Pranken, (#132) (1945 November 3), November 1930
      - German treatment of Italian soldiers taken prisoner or interned after the surrender of Italy to the Allies (#133) (), 1945 November 3
      - Report on interrogation of leading German official of the WAST on the Wehrmacht casualties during the war (#134) (), 1945 November 8
      - Strength of the "General SS" as on with figures on its pre-war complement (Greater German Reich) (#135) (1945 November 5), June 30, 1942
      - Duplicates (#136)
      - The Nacht und Nebel Erlass: Prosecution of offenses against the Reich in the occupied territories (#137) (), 1945 November 15
      - The activities of the "People's Court" in years (#138) (1945 November 15), 1942-1943
      - German policy in Poland,. Extracts from diaries of Hans Frank (#139) (1945 November 15), 1939-1945
      - Duplicates (#140)
      - German preparations for air war, (#141) (1945 December 14), April 1939
      - Nazis prepare to take over power, (#142) (1945 November 23), 1932
      - Police executions and special courts in the Kattowitz District, (#143) (1945 November 23), 1941
      - Quashing of prosecutions of murders and assailants of political prisoners due to pressure of political police (#144) (, 1945 December 13
      - Political and SS interference in administration of justice (#145) (), 1945 December 15
      - Duplicates (#146)
      - Aryanisation of Jewish property in Gau Pranken, (#147), November 1938-1942
      - Execution by security police (Sipo) of 135,567 Jews, communists, and mentally afflicted persons in Baltic States (#148) (), 1945 December 1
      - Duplicates (#149)
      - Quashing by political police of investigations and prosecutions ordered by the Staatsministerium der Justiz (#150) (), 1945 November 29
      - Duplicates (#151)
      - Duplicates (#152)
      - Schacht's attitude towards the Nazi anti-Jewish policy,. Documents from file entitled "Judenfrage" (#153), August-December 1935
      - Hitler plans to attack Czechoslovakia and Austria. Minutes of a meeting between Hitler, the Cs-in-C of the three services, etc. (#154) (), 1945 December 5
      - German General Staff's negotiations with Finland concerning the attack on Russia (#155) (), 1945 December 5
      - Doenitz orders resistance to the last, (#156) (1945 December 14), April 1945
      - Nazi management of Austrian plebiscite, (#157) (1945 December 12), April 1938
      - The German Intelligence Service and coordination of its research agencies (from private papers of SS-Hastuf Hrallert) (#158) (), 1945 December 21
      - Nazi proposal for the absorption of Hungary (#159)
      - Speech made by Speer at the Gauleiter Rally in Munich,, on taking over from Todt (#160), 24 February 1942
      - Program for the employment in Germany of workers from occupied countries () (#161) (1946 January 1), 1944
      - German preparations for war in (#162) (1946 January 3), 1935
      - Nazi plan, dated, for snatching a political victory out of the jaws of military defeat (#163) (1946 January 4), 15 March 1945
      - Neurath accepts Mussolini's offer to issue dementis on the prosecution of Jews in Germany (Letter from Neurath to Hitler, ) (#164) (1946 January 2), 2 February 1933
      - Speech by Hitler at the Gauleiter conference in Berlin on 2, outlining the Nazi principles of government (#165), February 1934
      - Duplicates (#166)
      - Shooting of three hundred and twenty-eight civilian prisoners in Minsk by the SD in (#167) (1946 January 10), January 1942
      - Ribbentrop explains to the Army the nature of the mission of Abetz on the latter's promotion to be Ambassador to the Vichy Government, dated (#168) (1946 January 14), 3 August 1940
      - Murder, rape, plunder, and other horrors, perpetrated by the Germans in Poland, (#169) (1946 January 22), November 1939 - January 1940
  - S-File (Box 6)
    - Order concerning prohibition of listening to foreign broadcasts (#1) (Folder 6: 1)
    - Activities of stormtroopers on German "Innere Front" (#2)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#3)
    - Scheme of German military censorship (#4)
    - German home morale (#5)
    - German warning against Allied leaflets (#6)
    - German soldiers describe Allied firepower (#7)
    - Danger of typhus, etc., through insufficient draining system (#8)
    - Lack of equipment and uniforms (#9)
    - Re arrest of Oberst Stioda (#10)
    - Duplicates (#11)
    - Altar for the Führer in every dugout or section (#12)
    - German leaflet: Mistreatment of prisoners by the British (#13)
    - Order demanding conservation of civilian morale in France (#14)
    - Commander Cherbourg complains about insufficient equipment (#15)
    - Evidence of partisan activities in France (#16)
    - Extracts from soldiers' diaries (#17)
    - Order re leadership and morale and countering enemy propaganda (#18)
    - Order re "corner for the Führer in troop quarters" (#19)
    - Wehrmacht pamphlet telling soldiers "why they have to fight" (#20)
    - German soldiers on bunkers (#21)
    - Decree forcing French civilian population to repair communications (#22)
    - Order re food German units are allowed to buy in France (#23)
    - Securing of classified material in the event of enemy attack (#24)
    - German unit with no telephone communication owing to lack of wire (#25)
    - Drunken German soldiers destroy French furniture, etc. (#26)
    - Pattern of Nazi ideological training in the Army (#27)
    - Order revealing method of spreading leaflets for Americans (#28)
    - Detention units in the German army also in West (#29)
    - German soldiers' letters from the West (#30)
    - Kreisleiter on evacuation of town (#31)
    - Ten commandments for German soldiers in Paris (#32)
    - Morale of German soldiers in France before the invasion (#33)
    - Death sentence for cowardice (#34)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#35)
    - Order re terror against partisans and civilians in France (#36)
    - Order of the Day to soldiers in 14th Army: "There is no way back" (#37)
    - Extracts from five diaries (#38)
    - Diary of a German soldier (#39)
    - Notes by German soldiers revealing effect of Goebbels' propaganda (#40)
    - Secret directives against partisans, enemy propaganda, desertions (#41)
    - Report of prisoners from the East are sent from Stalags to the West (#42)
    - Report of conference with adjutant of Flak unit (#43)
    - Order of the Day 716th Infantry Division concerning promotions (#44)
    - Censorship report re subversive remarks of Polish soldier (#45)
    - Confidential directions re political developments in Brittany (#46)
    - Division Roder: Rewards for foreigners (#47)
    - Death sentence for deserter, carried out in France (#48)
    - Order of the Day by Kesselring (#49)
    - Secret order re labor volunteers (#50) (Folder 6: 2)
    - Order re French population to build paratroop and glider obstacles (#51)
    - Files dealing with sabotage, Allied propaganda, etc. (#52)
    - Diaries of German soldiers in the Cherbourg area (#53)
    - Soldier sentenced to death for desertion - execution after war (#54)
    - Seven death sentences on officers for subversive activities (#55)
    - Disciplinary punishment of German soldiers (#56)
    - Order by Organization Todt re treatment of forced laborers (#57)
    - Anti-Bolshevik Russian convicted in German Army (#58)
    - Extracts from civilian letters (#59)
    - Poster asking French population to build obstacles against airborne troops (#60)
    - Foreigners in German Army, increase of subversive activity (#61)
    - Secret order authorizing killing of French partisans and civilians under suspicion (#62)
    - Order re hedgehog tactics against partisans (#63)
    - Order against "panic" (#64)
    - Göring asks for higher efforts in the Luftwaffe, praises Allies (#65)
    - Secret order by Hitler prohibiting threat with court martial to avoid desertions (#66)
    - Order re precautions by German soldiers against attacks by French civilians (#68)
    - German soldiers think "doodlebugs" mean end of war (#69)
    - Report re frontline radio propaganda against American troops (#70)
    - Diary of German soldier describing beginning of invasion (#71)
    - Report on secret meeting of commanding generals and Hitler, Himmler, Rosenberg, etc. (#72)
    - War-weary soldier still believes in the wisdom of the Führer (#73)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters (#74)
    - Directives re handling of Allied propaganda material, leaflets (#75)
    - Letters from Vienna: Allies have firm grip on French territory (#76)
    - Secret order: Anglo-Americans will use poison gas in the invasion (#77)
    - Secret order re "enemy sabotage" (#78)
    - Secret order re details on manhunt on French civilians (#79)
    - Secret instructions about theft of personal papers by enemy secret service (#80)
    - Seven cases of punishment against German soldiers in Western France (#81)
    - Confession of faith by a German soldier (#82)
    - Order stating desertions of soldiers to "partisan bands" (#83)
    - Order banning leave for troops and exemptions (#84)
    - German chief of armor issues order against grinding troops (#85)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers (#86)
    - German Army directives concerning soldiers' complaints (#87)
    - Rundstedt on morale of Allied troops (#88)
    - Order re jamming of Soldatensender Calais (#89)
    - Order of the Day C-in-C, 14th Army: Too many have raised the white flag (#90)
    - Questionnaire for Nazi-Propaganda interrogators of Allied POWs (#91)
    - Diary of German soldier: This war is lost for Germany (#92)
    - Notes of an Austrian deserter who gave himself up to Allied troops (#93)
    - German leaflets dropped to Anglo-American troops in Italy (#94)
    - Report on a tour of inspection by French collaborationist journalist (#95)
    - Secret order re blocking of highways against partisans (#96)
    - Special order re education of 17-18 year old HJ boys (#97)
    - Ill treatment in the SS (#98)
    - Atrocity stories of the German High Command (#99)
    - Limited operational value of German unit (#100) (Folder 6: 3)
    - Nazi war song (#101)
    - Foreign volunteer found unreliable because of defeatist letters (#102)
    - Extracts from soldiers' letters from the Cherbourg area (#103)
    - Soldiers tend to prolong leave by falsification of leave passes (#104)
    - German CO bolsters up troops' morale (#105)
    - Warning against falsification of camouflaged Allied leaflets (#106)
    - Twenty lapses of military discipline in 709th Infantry Division (#107)
    - Increased rations for troops working in mine laying, etc. (#108)
    - Files of SS-Pz. Div. "Hitlerjugend," court martial of SS-man, etc. (#109)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in the Cherbourg area (#110)
    - Report by Organization Todt re Dutch agitators (#111)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers (#112)
    - Secret order re training of troops: Allied superiority, etc. (#113)
    - Disintegration of troops in Italy, special units for detaining deserters (#114)
    - Goebbels forbids the word "Katastrophe" in the beginning of 1944 (#115)
    - SS-Pz. Dv. "Reichsführer" to fight to the last bullet (#116)
    - General scheme of German Press and Information Service in foreign countries (#117)
    - Secret directive by F.O. (German) for German embassies in European capitals (#118)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in the East (#119)
    - Soldiers' letters re unknown weapon (#120)
    - Excerpt from speech by Fieldmarshal Keitel in Bad Schachen (#121)
    - Extract from diary of German officer: Lt. Rebensdorf (#122)
    - Order re requisition of radio sets in France (#123)
    - Diary of German soldier describing conditions in detention units (#124)
    - Death sentences for German soldiers for conspiring with French civilians (#125)
    - Shortage of vehicles and fuel (#126)
    - Request by German unit for medical material (#127)
    - Warnings against sabotage and attacks on German troops (Italy) (#128)
    - Order re poisoning of food by the enemy (#129)
    - Three diaries: Pole describes opening of invasion, etc. (#130)
    - Suicides and suicide attempts of German soldiers (#131)
    - Extracts from civilian letters (#132)
    - Extracts from letter written by Waffen-SS member (#133)
    - Two letters from soldiers criticizing conditions in the Army (#134)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#135)
    - From where do French partisans get their ammunition? (#136)
    - List of scarce medical supplies (#137)
    - 12th SS-Pz. Div. shortage of medical supplies, etc. (#138)
    - Order re treatment and evacuation of Allied POWs (#139)
    - Order re precautions against the invasion (#140)
    - Order re ammunition supply, failure in production and quality (#141)
    - Extracts from letters written by SS-leaders (#142)
    - Order re instances of low discipline of troops (#143)
    - Suicides in SS-Pz. Div. "Hitlerjugend" (#144)
    - New penalties for "crimes" (#145)
    - Order re supplies to be destroyed in case of withdrawal (#146)
    - Order by Chief of Staff re working time (#147)
    - Directives for conduct of personnel during operations (#148)
    - Security regulations with G.A.F. mail service in Paris (#149)
    - Danes protest against German guards when on rescue work (#150) (Folder 6: 4)
    - Duplicates (#151)
    - Invasion diary of German soldier (#152)
    - Extracts from letters written by members of the SS-Pz. Div. "Hitlerjugend" (#153)
    - Directive for propaganda inside the German units (Eastern volunteers) (#154)
    - German views on the Danubian region (#155)
    - Duplicates (#156)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers (#157)
    - Duplicates (#158)
    - Amnesty by Mussolini for partisans; details of supplies for partisans (#159)
    - Diary of German soldier (#160)
    - Ill treatment of volunteers from the East (#161)
    - List of soldiers punished for insubordination, thefts, etc. (#162)
    - V. Schlieben orders to make a stand; death for everyone who retreats (#163)
    - Letter from NSKK Standartenführer: Was treated badly on Army because a Nazi (#164)
    - Letter from Brigadeführer re morale in Berlin, etc. (#165)
    - Duplicates (#166)
    - Regimental order re morale of German troops in France (#167)
    - Interrogation teams of German F.O. in the front line (#168)
    - Leibstandarte Adolf Hitler sentences for corruption, etc. (#169)
    - Directives for requisitioning and warnings against looting in France (#170)
    - Shortage of cable and wire (#171)
    - Shortage of trucks and ammunition, 21st Pz. Division (#172)
    - Kampfgruppe Rauch order to defend Caen to last bullet (#173)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#174)
    - Order re Geneva Convention being observed by Anglo-American troops (#175)
    - Directives re handling of Allied POWs (#176)
    - French police and gendarmes - cooperation with French partisans (#177)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#178)
    - Letter of Feldwebel: Americans fight well, are humane to German POWs (#179)
    - Threat of court martial in cases of loss of small arms (#180)
    - German leaflet dropped on Allied troops (#181)
    - Nazis who listen to Allied broadcasts (#182)
    - Measures taken against French partisans, methods for recruiting forced labor (#183)
    - Nazi leaders to be trained as front-line officers (#184)
    - Commander of Caen: Measures against "internal unrest," sabotage (#185)
    - Secret order re allotment of ammunition in the West (#186)
    - Battalion Com. complains his battalion was abused as cowards (#187)
    - Commander Parachute Unit to give his oath to fight to the end (#188)
    - Desertions, fear and nervousness, losses in battle, etc. (#189)
    - Older soldiers are setting a bad example in discipline for the younger (#190)
    - The Führer's order after the invasion (#191)
    - Plundering by German soldiers created chaos behind the lines (#192)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#193)
    - Extracts from letters written by German soldiers in France (#194)
    - Extract from letter describing effects of air raid on Braunschweig (#195)
    - Address by General Schack to 272nd Inf. Div. (#196)
    - Three desertions reports on foreigners in the German army (#197)
    - Soldier's letter fed up on account of not getting any home leave (#198)
    - Zeitzler on "Panzerschreck" (very different in reality from propaganda) (#199)
    - Flak units' directives for the defense of trains against partisans (#200) (Folder 6: 5)
    - List of deserters from Regt. 897 (#201)
    - Evidence that Germans cannot replace service trucks (#202)
    - Artillery ammunition is available only in limited quantities (#203)
    - Evacuation of French civilians from areas behind the front line (#204)
    - Special Hitler order to German soldiers after 20 July plot (#205)
    - Eastern battalion in the West promised to "liberate" Russia (#206)
    - Proclamation to non-German soldiers (#207)
    - It is not possible to send reserves to the front with full equipment (#208)
    - Postwar employment plans for soldiers (#209)
    - Battle experiences of "Panzer-Lehr-Division" (#210)
    - Special Admiralty order re prevention and punishment of sabotage (#211)
    - German paratroopers young and inexperienced for fighting terrorists (#212)
    - Extracts from letters written by soldiers in France (#213)
    - Shortages (#214)
    - O.T. records destroyed in raid on Berlin (#215)
    - Russian POWs transported to West to work on fortifications (#216)
    - Allies succeed in snatching a German parachutist. Germans failed (#217)
    - Allied tank attack shakes the nerves of young Germans (#218)
    - Orders and news after July 20 plot (#219)
    - Lack of fuel and decisive cut in rations for German units (#220)
    - Catastrophic situation in supply of German service trucks (#221)